# **JAMES SHOEMAKE**

# Front End Engineer

# **SUMMARY**

Professional software engineer with over 10 years of experience developing Front End and Full Stack Web applications focused on aesthetically pleasing user-friendly design using modern tools and languages such as HTML/CSS/JavaScript, React, Jest, SQL, and NoSQL databases.

## WORK HISTORY & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

#### Full Stack Applications Developer | Data Analyst

Essential Knowledge Systems Petal, MS / August 2019 - Present

- Designed and Implemented a React web application which manages educational course materials; allows instructors to create assignments and students to take assignments and receive feedback.
- Developed React application utilizing the Open Source Routing Machine project and OpenStreetMap based directions for drivers delivering products around the Hattiesburg and Petal, MS area.
- Ported a PyTorch Machine learning model, mTAN, into PyTorch-Lightning allowing the formerly Single-GPU model to run on multi-GPU and multi-node hardware.
- Co-Authored 2 Machine learning papers: one based on Parallel computing via PyTorch-Lightning and another comparing Transfer learning models.

#### Full Stack Web Developer | Lead Search Developer

Howard Technology Ellisville, MS / May 2013 - Present

- Developed a new search class, search landing page and predictive search feature for the Howard website relaunches; implemented utilizing ColdFusion, JavaScript, and Fusion by Lucidworks, resulting an increase in customer searches by 85%.
- Instrumental contributor to the 2018 redesign of the Howard websites, designed UX for customer account management, general website layout, Implemented Google Analytics filters, and dashboards.
- Created Howard medical customer opportunity signup system leading to over 100 new customers and over \$1 million in medical equipment sales.
- Established first Jest based JavaScript testing for Howard websites;
   wrote styling guide for Howard JavaScript programming.

- <u>James.shoemake1@gmail.com</u>
- 601 862 3380
- Petal, MS
- github.com/jamesshoemake

## SKILLS

HTML/CSS/JavaScript
React/Jest/Puppeteer
ColdFusion
SQL/MS SQL Server
Git
Node
C++ | Python
Redis | MongoDB
PyTorch
Linux

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master of Business Administration

USM, Hattiesburg, MS 2018 - 2019

Applied Technology, BS Minor Computer Science USM, Hattiesburg, MS 2016 - 2018

Computer Information Systems Technology, AAS Jones College, Ellisville, MS 2010 - 2012

#### OTHER EXPERIENCE

# BootCountryOnline.com

Full Stack Developer 2012 - 2013

#### **USMC**

Corporal of Marines 2005 - 2009